<resources>

    <string name="app_name">Grupo5Reto2</string>
    <string name="title_activity_maps">Get to know Muzkiz!</string>
    <string name="open">Open</string>
    <string name="close">Close</string>
    <!-- TODO: Remove or change this placeholder text -->


    <!-- Menu Principal -->
    <string name="hintUser">Username</string>
    <string name="hintClase">Classroom</string>
    <string name="start">Start</string>
    <string name="othersUsers">Savegames:</string>
    <string name="eresProfesor"><u>IF YOU ARE PROFESSOR, PRESS HERE</u></string>
    <string name="partidaguardada">Touch to continue this savegame</string>


    <!-- Map Activity -->
    <!-- Menu -->
    <string name="modes">Modes</string>
    <string name="puntuation">Score</string>
    <string name="others">Others</string>
    <string name="freeMode">Free Mode</string>
    <string name="guidedMode">Guided Mode</string>
    <string name="profesorMode">Teacher Mode</string>
    <string name="yourProgress">Your Progress</string>
    <string name="ranking">Ranking</string>
    <string name="aboutUs">About Us</string>
    <string name="logOut">Log Out</string>

    <!-- Playa La Arena -->
    <string name="gameLaArenaHondartza">La Arena Beach</string>
    <string name="cardsMatch">Right!</string>

    <!-- Hermita -->
    <string name="gameHermitaDePobeña">Pobela Hermitage</string>



    <!-- Fundicion -->
    <string name="gameFundicion">Pobela Foundry</string>

    <!-- Castillo Muñatones -->
    <string name="gameCastilloMuñatones">Muñatones Castle</string>
    <string name="explanationCastilloMuñatones">Muñatones Castle is located in Muskiz, Bizkaia.
        Somorrostro is a town in the valley, formed by the Barbadun river.
        It has around 7,500 inhabitants and the municipality is located in a protected natural space.
        We will find this castle we are talking about in front of the Petronor company refinery.
        Although it is called a castle, it is a tower house.
        It should be noted that it is not just any tower, but that of Lope García de Salazar,
        One of the most prominent personalities of the Middle Ages in Bizkaia. It was built in 1339,
        at the end of the aforementioned period.
        The current castle of Muñatones was built and destroyed over the centuries.
        with all kinds of wins and losses. Today, castle of Muñatones
        It is the only castle in Bizkaia that has preserved most of the characteristics of its time. </string>

    <!-- Itsaslur Ibilbidea -->
    <string name="gameItsaslurIbilbidea">Itsaslur Route</string>

    <string name="waiting">Waiting</string>
    <string name="waitingExplanation">You have to wait for the teacher to finish giving the explanation</string>
    <string name="itsaslurQ1">Where have we entered the route?</string>
    <string name="itsaslurQ2">What have we seen in the route</string>
    <string name="itsaslurQ3">What have we found halfway?</string>
    <string name="itsaslurQ4">Where can we take a bath?</string>
    <!-- San Juan gaua-->
    <string name="gameSanJuan">San Juan Night</string>
    <string name="explanationSanJuan">St Juan is known as the shortest day of the year, although in fact actual date is June 21st.
        When is the summer solstice celebrated? The adaptation made by Christianism explains that it does not coincide with the summer solstice. Tonight with San Joan
        will be celebrated, fire burns everything, fire is desired and summer will be welcomed. In addition to being a magical day, it can also ward off bad spirits or what happened
        breaking with bad things. In the past, these fires were lit to give more power to the sun and thus extend the light.
        In the past, it was celebrated as a pagan festival, as the sun was considered a god. With the advent of Christianity, the celebration changed, but it has never lost its essence.
        Nowadays, tradition and rituals are mixed, and everyone celebrates as they want, dancing around the fire, jumping over it, enjoying the night.
        The origin of this date is the day of the birth of Saint John the Baptist, as his father Zacharias ordered a fire to be lit to announce the birth of his son.
        In Muskizen, the descent of the torches, which starts at the station at 22:30, is of great importance. Then, around 11:30 p.m., the fireworks start, followed by a verbena.
        That night, people who come to Muskize light torches up to the old warehouse of Petronor, together with the whistlers, and then throw the torches into the bonfire of San Jorge.
</string>
    <!-- Pantalla felicitacion-->
    <string name="congratulations1">You did it, friend!</string>
    <string name="congratulations2">You have solved the challenge</string>
    <string name="GoToMap">Go to Map</string>
    <!-- Pantalla felicitacion-->
    <string name="gamePuenteRomano">Roman bridge of Pobeña</string>

    <string name="Continue">Continue</string>
    <string name="hello_blank_fragment">Hello blank fragment</string>
    <string name="puente_romano_enunciado_1">The Romanesque bridge of El Pobal leads to the El Pobal ironworks, over the Barbadun river. XIII. It was built in the century, and Muskiz was the oldest bridge in the city.</string>
    <string name="puente_romano_enunciado_2">The Barbadun River passed through the center of Muskize, so they had to build a bridge to be able to move around the town without any problem. Thanks to this, people moved from Galdames and Sopuerta to Muskize. This bridge was necessary due to demographic problems.</string>
    <string name="puente_romano_enunciado_3">The bridge is made of stone. It had two arched eyes, but today it has one, as the other sank in the Carlistlands, and a concrete walkway has been built in its place today. It is approximately two meters wide and has no protective walls. To prevent the bridge from falling, a large pillar has been built. It is still passable today, but it has not been used for a long time.</string>
    <string name="puente_romano_preg_1">In what century was the Romanesque bridge of Pobal built?</string>
    <string name="puente_romano_preg_2">What river crosses this bridge?</string>
    <string name="puente_romano_preg_3">What was this bridge built for?</string>
    <string name="puente_romano_preg_4">What is the bridge made of?</string>
    <string name="puente_preg_1_res_1">3th Century</string>
    <string name="puente_preg_1_res_2">13th Century , oldest from Muskiz</string>
    <string name="puente_preg_1_res_3">20th Century</string>
    <string name="puente_preg_2_res_1">Barbadun river</string>
    <string name="puente_preg_2_res_2">Nerbioi river</string>
    <string name="puente_preg_2_res_3">Kadagua river</string>
    <string name="puente_preg_3_res_1">It was built as decoration</string>
    <string name="puente_preg_3_res_2">For animals to pass from one side to the other</string>
    <string name="puente_preg_3_res_3">So that people from Galdames and Sopuerta can pass to Muskiz</string>
    <string name="puente_preg_4_res_1">Wood</string>
    <string name="puente_preg_4_res_2">Stone</string>
    <string name="puente_preg_4_res_3">Iron</string>
    <string name="reiniciar_juego">Restart</string>
    <string name="jugar">Play</string>
    <string name="volver">Return</string>
    <string name="incorrecto">Wrong</string>
    <string name="siguiente">Next</string>
    <string name="primero">First</string>
    <string name="anterior">Previous</string>
    <string name="ultimo">Last</string>
    <string name="mar_revuelto">Rough</string>
    <string name="mar_tranquilo">Calm</string>
    <string name="upv1">Uxue Cerrada</string>
    <string name="upv2">Irati Bargos</string>
    <string name="upv3">Oihane Baz</string>
    <string name="upv4">Aitor del Pozo</string>
    <string name="tx1">Jon Gonzalez</string>
    <string name="tx2">Eder Torres</string>
    <string name="tx3">Daniel Diez</string>
    <string name="tx4">Youssef Ait</string>
    <!-- Descripciones -->
    <string name="DescripcionCastillo">Ultimo</string>
    <string name="DescripcionLaarena">Ultimo</string>
    <string name="DescripcionPuente">Ultimo</string>
    <string name="DescripcionBurdinola">Ultimo</string>
    <string name="Descripcionermita">Ultimo</string>
    <string name="Descripcionitzalsur">Ultimo</string>
    <string name="DescripcionSanjuan">Ultimo</string>
    <string name="IrPuzzle">Go to puzzle</string>
    <string name="Marinero1">The watchtowers and signaling posts were very simple structures, and Pobeña\'s in particular, it was created between the 16th century. and 18th century. In addition to meeting the needs of the mussels, this vantage point was used for fishing to manage the commercial traffic with iron ore from the mines of Somorrostro and the iron from the forges of the Barbadun river, with the help of the small ships that traveled.</string>
    <string name="Nosotros">We are a group of UPV Teaching students. Together with a group of students from the CIFP Txurdinaga we have carried out an application so that the primary school children of Muskiz can learn while playing.</string>
    <string name="Idea">Devised by:</string>
    <string name="Desarrollo">Developers:</string>
    <string name="DescProf">Area for the teacher to view the answers to some games. Finally, he will be the one in charge of controlling some of the other games.</string>
    <string name="ResButPuente">Go to roman bridge</string>
    <string name="ResButPaseo">Go to Itsaslur</string>
    <string name="ResButCastillo">Go to the castle</string>
    <string name="ResButHermita">Go to the hermitage</string>
    <string name="Comprobar">Check</string>
    <string name="ResTxtCas">The final image of the puzzle must be the castle. This is how it should look like:</string>
    <string name="ResTxtHermita">The solutions to the game are divided into: rough and calm sea, here are the solutions to the different photos:</string>
    <string name="ResTranquilo">Calm sea:</string>
    <string name="ResRevuelto">Rough sea:</string>
    <string name="Aceptar">Goodbye</string>
    <string name="txtLejos">You are to far from the point! Get closer to play.</string>
    <string name="txtGuiado">You are in guide mode</string>
    <string name="txtLibre">You are in free mode</string>
    <string name="Crear">Create</string>
    <string name="Informacion">Please, write you\'re name, you\'re classroom\'s name (you\'re pupils will use it as a password to enter in the match) and the password that\'s given in the user manual.</string>
    <string name="Marinero2">The hermitage of Nuestra Señora del Socorro was built in 1768 and is located near the mouth of the Barbadun River. They call it Nuestra Señora del Socorro because they used it when there was danger to ask for help, which made it one of the favorites of the sailors of Pobeña, who were always at sea when they went fishing. Therefore, before starting to fish, the boats stopped there, went up to ask for protection and checked the state of the sea, to decide whether it was convenient to embark or not.</string>
    <string name="Bienvenido">Welcome to Muskiz!</string>
    <string name="CrearSala">The time has come to create a new room so your pupils can join in!</string>
</resources>